Urban League of Northeastern New York; Records apap008
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Urban League of Northeastern New York Records
1966-1987
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
apap008
8.5 cubic ft.
Since its establishment in 1966 as the Urban League of the Albany N.Y. Area, the Urban League of Northeastern New York has campaigned for voter registration, housing, education, social services and other issues of concern to African Americans and others in the New York State Capital District.
Administrative History
The Urban League of the Albany Area was incorporated as a not-for-profit agency on May 6, 1966 ["Operation Intercept", Grant Proposal. Urban League of the Albany Area. (Albany, NY: 1977). p. 1].
The Urban League of the Albany Area is one of 113 affiliates of the National League. At some point, the date is not clear, the Urban League of the Albany Area changed their name to the Urban League of Northeastern New York. The mission of the Urban League is to enable blacks and other minority group members to cultivate and exercise their full potential on par with all other Americans [Annual Report. Urban League of the Albany Area. (Albany, NY: 1987). p. 4]. The Urban League aspires to fulfill its mission by providing those human services found to be insufficient or nonexistent in urban areas. The League maintains departments which assist clients in the areas of health, education, housing, and employment. The services are provided free of charge and are made available through funding provided by individual and corporate contributions and program funding from state and federal agencies.
Management of the Urban League is under the control of a Board of Directors. Elected by the membership, Board members serve three year terms during which they review and establish policy within the prescribed guidelines of the National Urban League. The Executive Director reports directly to the Board and is responsible for the daily operations of the Urban League.
Directors of the Urban League of Northeastern New York
Aaron R. Dare, 1996-2000
L. Lloyd Stewart, 1992-1996
Clem Lloyd, 1992*
Jamie D. Bracey, 1991-1992
Joseph A. Griggs, 1991*
Lawrence Burwell, 1990-1991
Clarence Swanston, 1988-1990
Barbara Winters, 1986-1987
Lloyd J. Oxford, 1982-1985
Raoul A. Davis, 1981-1982
Francis Alphonso, 1980-1981*
Colwyn Allen, 1979-1980
Johnsie Williams, 1978-1979*
Lawrence Burwell, 1968-1978
Carter L. Lowe, 1966-1968
* acting directors
Scope and Contents
Urban League of Northeastern New York is a not-for-profit, multicultural organization committed to the improvement of human services to blacks and other minorities. The records of the Urban League of Northeastern New York include annual reports, meeting minutes and newsletters. The records are divided into three series, Subject Files (1968-87); Meeting Minutes (1968-87); and the National Urban League Files (1966-87).
As an affiliate of a national organization the Urban League of Northeastern New York is obligated to support and follow mandates from the national headquarters. Recent National Urban League issues have been voter education (1983) and public school education (1985). The voter education drive was a proceed to the voter registration drives of the 1960s. Having experienced major declines in federal funding during the conservative Reagan Administration, the National Urban League established the voter education drive in the attempts to have minorities register and vote in the 1984 presidential election. As part of the voter education drive, the National Urban League issued reports on the Reagan administration regarding setbacks in civil rights legislation, the disproportionate spending allowances between social services and military spending, and the nomination of Robert Bork for Supreme Court justice. The Albany Urban League carried on a campaign similar to that of the national campaign.
Higher education was also a major concern for the National Urban League during the 1980s. Cutbacks in federal aid saw minority enrollment fall to new lows. The National Urban League mandate on the issue was the sponsoring of full and partial academic scholarship to worthy minority high school seniors. In response the Urban League of the Albany Area established several scholarships with the help of area banks, corporations, colleges, and universities (1987).
Aside from NUL issues the local affiliate was also responsible for innovative solutions to community problems. The Teen Pregnancy Program (1980-) and the Fatherhood Program (1984-90) were developed by the Urban League of Northeastern New York to address the growing dilemma of teen pregnancy in the Capitol District. In the area of education the Urban League of Northeastern New York has sponsored the Adolescent Vocational Exploration Program (known hereafter as the AVE Program)(1984-). Designed to motivate and prepare high school students for work, the AVE program is operated in conjunction with the Job Training Partnership Administration and the State Education Department. A third area in which the Albany League is highly visible is the Housing Counseling Program (1979-). The Housing Department within the Urban League provides mortgage default counseling, housing referral, and home purchase counseling to first time buyers.
There are gaps in some of the most important records of the collection such as the Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, Executive Directors, Annual Reports, and Departmental Reports. The 1970s go almost totally undocumented. This may be a result of the changes in leadership at the Urban League of Northeastern New York. Since 1978 there have been a total of six appointed or acting executive directors. In light of such turnover records may have been lost or destroyed.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is divided into four file series.
Acquisition Information
All items in this manuscript group were donated to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, by the Urban League of the Albany Area in 1990.
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted.
African Americans and Civil Rights Organizations; African Americans -- Civil rights -- New York (State).; African Americans -- Education -- New York (State).; Birth control -- New York (State).; Abortion services -- Law and legislation -- New York (State).; New York (State) -- Societies and clubs.; Minutes.; Neighborhood and Community Associations; Albany, New York; Ethnic Groups; Social Activists and Public Advocates; National Urban League.; National Urban League. Northeastern Regional Office.
- Executive Board Files, 1968; 1979-1986; 1; 0.5 cubic ft.
  Scope and Contents
  The Executive Board Files contain the meeting minutes of the Board of Directors (1968, 1979-1985) and the Executive Committee (1984-1986) include correspondence with the NUL, personnel matters, and correspondence with Albany, New York Mayor Thomas Whalen III and NUL President John E. Jacob. They were maintained as a record of the activities of the Albany Urban League in its affiliation with the National Urban League and as a community based organization in the Capitol District. The Executive Director's Reports served as monthly overviews of the day-to-day operations of the Albany Urban League. The smallest of the series' the Executive Board Files are incomplete. The Urban League of Northeastern New York began in 1966 but gaps in the series leave the 1960s and 1970s largely undocumented. Executive Board Files produced after 1987 are in the possession of the Urban League of Northeastern New Yorke.
  Arrangement
  Arranged in three sub series ("Meeting Minutes", "Executive Committee Minutes", "Executive Director's Reports"), and arranged chronologically thereunder.
  - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 1968 (Box 1 (1-Executive Board Files), Folder 1)
  - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 1979 (Box 1 (1-Executive Board Files), Folder 2)
  - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 1980 (Box 1 (1-Executive Board Files), Folder 3)
  - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 1981 (Box 1 (1-Executive Board Files), Folder 4)
  - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 1982 (Box 1 (1-Executive Board Files), Folder 5)
  - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 1983 (Box 1 (1-Executive Board Files), Folder 6)
  - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 1984 (Box 1 (1-Executive Board Files), Folder 7)
  - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 1985 (Box 1 (1-Executive Board Files), Folder 8)
  - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 1986 (Box 1 (1-Executive Board Files), Folder 9)
  - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 1987 (Box 1 (1-Executive Board Files), Folder 10)
  - Executive Committee Meeting Minutes, 1980 (Box 1 (1-Executive Board Files), Folder 11)
  - Executive Committee Meeting Minutes, 1982 (Box 1 (1-Executive Board Files), Folder 12)
  - Executive Committee Meeting Minutes, 1983 (Box 1 (1-Executive Board Files), Folder 13)
  - Executive Committee Meeting Minutes, 1984 (Box 1 (1-Executive Board Files), Folder 14)
  - Executive Committee Meeting Minutes, 1985 (Box 1 (1-Executive Board Files), Folder 15)
  - Executive Committee Meeting Minutes, 1986 (Box 1 (1-Executive Board Files), Folder 16)
  - Executive Committee Meeting Minutes, 1987 (Box 1 (1-Executive Board Files), Folder 17)
- Subject Files, 1968-1987; 2; 4 cubic ft.
  The Subject Files contain annual reports (1967, 1974-1978, 1982-1984, 1985, 1987-1988), annual dinner program (1975, 1978, 1982), general correspondence (1981-1987), and the annual meeting minutes (1970, 1975, 1980-1984). They were maintained as a record of the daily operations of the Urban League of Northeastern New York and provides an overview of the various programs with which the organization was involved. The documentation for this series is most complete in the years 1984-1987. Information recorded during the 1970s can also be found intermittently within the series. Missing from the series is a charter or any other material relating to the origins of the Albany Urban League. Also incomplete are records in the form of annual reports.
  Arranged alphabetically and chronologically thereunder.
  - "Action Alert", 1983 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 1)
  - Affiliate Board Development Module, 1985 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 2)
  - Affiliate Compliance Standards, 1984-1985 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 3)
  - Affiliates Information, 1985-1987 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 4)
  - Affiliate Newsletters/Annual Reports, 1986 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 5)
  - African-American Family, 1985 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 6)
  - Agency Relations Policies and Procedures, 1986 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 7)
  - Agreement Between the Coalition on Minority Employment and the Urban Development Corporation, 1982 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 8)
  - Albany Boys Club, 1984 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 9)
  - Albany-Colonie Regional Chamber of Commerce, 1983 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 10)
  - Albany-Colonie Regional Chamber of Commerce, 1984 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 11)
  - Albany-Colonie Regional Chamber of Commerce, 1985 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 12)
  - Albany County Affordable Housing Coalition, 1987 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 13)
  - Albany County Youth Bureau, 1970; 1976 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 14)
  - Albany Housing Authority, 1982 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 15)
  - Albany Teen Consortium, 1985-1987 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 16)
  - Allocations Appeal, 1984 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 17)
  - American Red Cross, 1984 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 18)
  - American Society for Public Administration, 1984 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 19)
  - Annual Affiliate Data Collection Report, 1981 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 20)
  - Annual Delegate Assembly, 1983 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 21)
  - Annual Delegate Assembly, 1984 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 22)
  - Annual Departmental Reports, 1982-1983 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 23)
  - Annual Meeting--Third, 1970 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 24)
  - Annual Meeting--Eighth, 1975 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 25)
  - Annual Meeting--Tenth, 1976 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 26)
  - Annual Meeting--Twelfth, 1978 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 27)
  - Annual Meeting--Thirteenth, 1979 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 28)
  - Annual Meeting--Fourteenth, 1980 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 29)
  - Annual Meeting--Fifteenth, 1982 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 30)
  - Annual Meeting--Seventeenth, 1984 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 31)
  - Annual Meeting--Nineteenth, 1986 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 32)
  - Annual Report--Albany, 1967 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 33)
  - Annual Report--Albany, 1968 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 34)
  - Annual Report--Albany, 1969 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 35)
  - Annual Report--Albany, 1976 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 36)
  - Annual Report--Albany, 1978 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 37)
  - Annual Report--Albany, 1982 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 38)
  - Annual Report--Albany, 1984 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 39)
  - Annual Report--Albany, 1987 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 40)
  - Annual Report--Albany, 1988 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 41)
  - Annual Report--Philadelphia, 1982 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 42)
  - Annual Report--Rochester, 1983 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 43)
  - Arbor Hill Development Corporation Report, 1983 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 44)
  - Arbor Hill Development Corporation Report, 1984 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 45)
  - Audit Report, 1980 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 46)
  - Audit Report, 1981; 1984 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 47)
  - Audit Report, 1986 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 48)
  - Baby Information Bureau Proposal, 1985 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 49)
  - Bicentennial of the Board of Regents and the University of the State of New York, 1983; 1984 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 50)
  - Black American Lobby for Africa and the Caribbean, 1984 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 51)
  - Black Arts and Cultural Festival, 1983 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 52)
  - Black Churches in Albany, Undated (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 53)
  - Black Community Organizations, Undated (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 54)
  - Black Cultural Studies Organization, 1982 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 55)
  - Black Heritage Association, 1983 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 56)
  - Black History Month, 1983-1984 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 57)
  - Black Media, Inc., 1984 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 58)
  - Black Pastors Association, 1987 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 59)
  - Board of Directors Manual, 1983 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 60)
  - Board of Directors Nominations, 1979 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 61)
  - Budget Allocation, 1985 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 62)
  - Business Relationship Improvement Plan, 1982 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 63)
  - By-laws of the Arbor Hill Development Corporation, Undated (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 64)
  - Capital Area Family Resources, Inc., 1975-1976 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 65)
  - Capital District African-American Heritage Association, 1986 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 66)
  - Capital District Builders of Educational Achievement, 1984 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 67)
  - Capital District Coalition Against Apartheid and Racism, 1985 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 68)
  - Capital District Community Loan Fund, 1986 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 69)
  - Capital District Essay Contest, 1983 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 70)
  - Capital District Minority Business Association, 1983 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 71)
  - Capital District Minority Sub-Contractors Association, 1985 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 72)
  - Capital District Municipal Population Projections, 1985 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 73)
  - Capital District Political Action Committee, 1983 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 74)
  - Capital District Regional Planning Commission, 1984 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 75)
  - Capital District Strategic Planning Committee, 1985 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 76)
  - Capital District Women's Political Caucus, 1986 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 77)
  - Capital Region Service Delivery Area, 1984 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 78)
  - Career Exploration Program, 1984 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 79)
  - Census Bureau, 1984 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 80)
  - Center for Resource Development, 1980 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 81)
  - Charity Donations, 1984 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 82)
  - Child Abuse and Neglect, 1984 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 83)
  - Citizens Council, 1984 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 84)
  - "Civil Rights Update", 1982-1983 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 85)
  - Community Based Organization Colloquium, 1983 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 86)
  - Columbia County Urban League, 1984 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 87)
  - Community-Police Relations Board, 1986 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 88)
  - Community Presentations, 1986 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 89)
  - Community Work Experience/Work Relief Program Contract, 1984 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 90)
  - Conference Calls, 1983 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 91)
  - Congressional Action Newsletter, 1985 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 92)
  - Connecticut Association for Human Services, 1986 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 93)
  - Constitution, 1986 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 94)
  - Constitutions of NUL Affiliates, 1983 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 95)
  - Constitution of the Life Policy--Advisory Board, Undated (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 96)
  - Consumer Credit Counseling Services, 1984 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 97)
  - Cooperative Extension, 1986 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 98)
  - Corporate Donations--Academic Scholarship Award, 1984 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 99)
  - Correspondence--General, 1981-1982 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 100)
  - Correspondence--General, 1983 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 101)
  - Correspondence--General, 1984 (Box 1 (2-Subject Files), Folder 102)
  - Correspondence--General, 1985 (Box 2 (2-Subject Files), Folder 1)
  - Correspondence--General, 1986 (Box 2 (2-Subject Files), Folder 2)
  - Correspondence--General, 1987 (Box 2 (2-Subject Files), Folder 3)
  - Correspondence--Outgoing, 1985 (Box 2 (2-Subject Files), Folder 4)
  - Correspondence with NUL, 1982 (Box 2 (2-Subject Files), Folder 5)
  - Council of Community Services, 1971 (Box 2 (2-Subject Files), Folder 6)
  - Council of Community Services Survey, 1983 (Box 2 (2-Subject Files), Folder 7)
  - Day Care Report, 1983 (Box 2 (2-Subject Files), Folder 8)
  - Department of Correctional Services, 1983 (Box 2 (2-Subject Files), Folder 9)
  - Department of Health and Human Services, 1987 (Box 2 (2-Subject Files), Folder 10)
  - Department of Social Services, 1985 (Box 2 (2-Subject Files), Folder 11)
  - Directory of Community Services-Fulton County, 1982 (Box 2 (2-Subject Files), Folder 12)
  - Domestic Violence Research Proposal, 1983 (Box 2 (2-Subject Files), Folder 13)
  - Dues Review Commission Meeting, 1982 (Box 2 (2-Subject Files), Folder 14)
  - Early Exposure to Financial Institutions, 1984 (Box 2 (2-Subject Files), Folder 15)
  - Eastern Regional Delegate Assembly, 1982 (Box 2 (2-Subject Files), Folder 16)
  - Eastern Regional Delegate Assembly, 1983 (Box 2 (2-Subject Files), Folder 17)
  - Eastern Regional Delegate Assembly, 1984 (Box 2 (2-Subject Files), Folder 18)
  - Eastern Regional Delegate Assembly, 1985 (Box 2 (2-Subject Files), Folder 19)
  - Eastern Regional Delegate Assembly, 1986 (Box 2 (2-Subject Files), Folder 20)
  - Eastern Regional Programmatic Conference, 1980 (Box 2 (2-Subject Files), Folder 21)
  - Eastern Regional Programmatic Conference, 1986 (Box 2 (2-Subject Files), Folder 22)
  - Eastern Regional Board Volunteer Training Guide, 1983 (Box 2 (2-Subject Files), Folder 23)
  - Economic Development and Employment, 1984 (Box 2 (2-Subject Files), Folder 24)
  - Education Initiative Task Force, 1986 (Box 2 (2-Subject Files), Folder 25)
  - Empire State Institute for the Performing Arts, 1983 (Box 2 (2-Subject Files), Folder 26)
  - Empire State Black Arts and Cultural Festival, 1984 (Box 2 (2-Subject Files), Folder 27)
  - Empire State Organization of Youth Employment Services, 1985 (Box 2 (2-Subject Files), Folder 28)
  - Employment Handbook, 1987 (Box 2 (2-Subject Files), Folder 29)
  - Employment/Training Office Monthly Report, 1986 (Box 2 (2-Subject Files), Folder 30)
  - Employment, Economic Development and Training, 1987 (Box 2 (2-Subject Files), Folder 31)
  - Equal Opportunity Policy, 1986 (Box 2 (2-Subject Files), Folder 32)
  - Essay Entries, 1986 (Box 2 (2-Subject Files), Folder 33)
  - Evaluation of the Family Planning Project, 1976 (Box 2 (2-Subject Files), Folder 34)
  - Executive Director's Proposed Work Plan, 1984 (Box 2 (2-Subject Files), Folder 35)
  - Executive Director's Report, 1967 (Box 2 (2-Subject Files), Folder 36)
  - Executive Director's Report, 1980 (Box 2 (2-Subject Files), Folder 37)
  - Executive Director's Report, 1981 (Box 2 (2-Subject Files), Folder 38)
  - Executive Director's Report, 1982 (Box 2 (2-Subject Files), Folder 39)
  - Executive Director's Report, 1984 (Box 2 (2-Subject Files), Folder 40)
  - Executive Director's Report, 1985 (Box 2 (2-Subject Files), Folder 41)
  - Executive Director's Report, 1986 (Box 2 (2-Subject Files), Folder 42)
  - Executive Director's Report, 1987 (Box 2 (2-Subject Files), Folder 43)
  - Executive Training Seminars, 1986 (Box 2 (2-Subject Files), Folder 44)
  - Evaluation of Communication Difficulties Between Board President and Executive Director, 1979 (Box 2 (2-Subject Files), Folder 45)
  - Family Day Festival, 1984 (Box 2 (2-Subject Files), Folder 46)
  - Family Planning Advocates of New York State, 1985 (Box 2 (2-Subject Files), Folder 47)
  - Family Planning Outreach and Follow-up Program, 1974 (Box 2 (2-Subject Files), Folder 48)
  - Family Planning Outreach and Follow-up Program, 1975 (Box 2 (2-Subject Files), Folder 49)
  - Family Planning Outreach and Follow-up Program, 1976-1977 (Box 2 (2-Subject Files), Folder 50)
  - Family Planning Proposal, 1976-1977 (Box 2 (2-Subject Files), Folder 51)
  - Fatherhood Newsletter, 1985 (Box 2 (2-Subject Files), Folder 52)
  - Fatherhood Project, 1986 (Box 2 (2-Subject Files), Folder 53)
  - Fatherhood Project Proposal, 1984 (Box 2 (2-Subject Files), Folder 54)
  - Field Assessment of Urban League of Northeastern New York, 1980 (Box 2 (2-Subject Files), Folder 55)
  - Field Operations Report, 1982 (Box 2 (2-Subject Files), Folder 56)
  - Finance Committee, 1982 (Box 2 (2-Subject Files), Folder 57)
  - Finance Committee, 1983 (Box 2 (2-Subject Files), Folder 58)
  - Finance Committee, 1985-1986 (Box 2 (2-Subject Files), Folder 59)
  - Finance Industry Pre-Employment Program, 1984 (Box 2 (2-Subject Files), Folder 60)
  - Ford Foundation Publications, 1984 (Box 2 (2-Subject Files), Folder 61)
  - Fund Raising Assistance to Affiliates, 1980 (Box 2 (2-Subject Files), Folder 62)
  - Health, Human Services, and Education, 1983 (Box 2 (2-Subject Files), Folder 63)
  - Health Professions Enrichment Pathways Project, 1980 (Box 2 (2-Subject Files), Folder 64)
  - Health Professions Enrichment Program, 1982 (Box 2 (2-Subject Files), Folder 65)
  - Home Energy Assistance Program, 1982-1983 (Box 2 (2-Subject Files), Folder 66)
  - Home Maintenance Workshop, 1984-1985 (Box 2 (2-Subject Files), Folder 67)
  - Horizons Exchange Program, 1986 (Box 2 (2-Subject Files), Folder 68)
  - Housing and Urban Development, 1987 (Box 2 (2-Subject Files), Folder 69)
  - Housing Counseling Program, 1984 (Box 2 (2-Subject Files), Folder 70)